Srivas Chennu

srivaschennu.github.io +44 7828 90 66 92 srivas@gmail.com



Profile

I specialise in translating the latest machine learning and statistical inference methods into scalable real-world applications in industry and academia. I have 14+ years of R&D experience, and a background in computer science. My research has been featured by the BBC, Wired Magazine, New Scientist and Discovery Channel. I have worked as a consultant and as a software engineer.

Employment

Senior ML Scientist Apple, UK 2019-present Developed large-scale deep learning and gradient boosting models for behavioural prediction Designed and deployed adaptive reinforcement learning based on probabilistic statistical inference **Assistant Professor** University of Kent, UK 2016-2019 Led health care AI project to predict biomarkers of consciousness from time series data 2010-2016 University of Cambridge, UK Senior Research Associate Developed statistical, ML and time series models for healthcare technology applications in neurology The Alan Turing Institute, UK **Visiting Researcher** 2018

• Software engineer in the *Oracle Reports* team, a part of Oracle's *Internet Application Server* platform

Oracle Corporation, India

Academic Achievements

Member of Technical Staff

Co-author of 50+ peer-reviewed publications in academic journals; h-index of 26 (as of 2022) Research career spanning academia (University of Cambridge, Kent) and industry (Apple)

Consulting

DataTiger (Acquired by Apple in 2018)

2018

2002-2004

• Applied ensemble machine learning for predicting customer behaviour

Rsrchxchange 2017

- Developed latent factor models with Apache Spark to power customisation of user experience
- Built neural network-based natural language processor with Spacy for content similarity analysis

Education

PhD in Computer Science	University of Kent, Canterbury, UK	2006-2009
MSc in Information and Communication Hamburg University of Technology		2004-2006
Systems	Hamburg, Germany	
BEng in Computer Science and	Visveswaraiah Technological University	1998-2002
Engineering	Bangalore, India	

Research and Technical Skills

- Big Data Modelling, Machine Learning
- Parametric, Non-parametric and Bayesian Statistics
- · Data Science and Visualisation
- Signal Processing and Time Series Analysis
- · Graph Theory and Network Analysis
- **Tools**: tensorflow, pytorch, pyro, scipy, pandas

- · Deep Neural Networks
- Applied Artificial Intelligence
- · Research Methods in Neuroscience
- Computer Networking and Security
- Operating Systems
- Languages: Python, JAVA, C++, C